Guide to the Morse Family Papers: William Reginald and Anne Crosse Kinney Morse
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Family Correspondence, 1909-1937; Series I
  - WRM to MM from Chengtu, 1933 November-December (Box 4, Folder 70)
    Describes a German Government official visit to China, the rise of the Communist party and WRM's fears regarding Communist success in Chinese government, financial and legal issues in the Chinese government, and WRM and ACM's holiday celebrations and plans.
  - ACM to MM from Chengtu, Peu Hsien, 1933 January-June (Box 4, Folder 71)
    Describes ACM's travel to and time in Peu Hsien, her support of MM's college work and future experiences, ACM's sketch and artwork processes, and daily life in Chengtu.
  - ACM to MM from Chengtu, Bei Liu Tin (Bei Lu Din), 1933 July-December (Box 4, Folder 72)
    Including description of nature and scenery that ACM comes across during the summer season, her meetings with the Fine Arts Committee, military affairs, art exhibition openings, the devastation of an earthquake, and life events in Bei Lu Din and Chengtu.
  - WRM to MM from Chengtu, 1934 January-June (Box 4, Folder 73)
    Describes WRM's advice to MM for her future profession, WRM resigning from the Deanship of medicine in order to have more freedom, MM filing legal papers for American citizenship, and WRM's report writing for the College of Medicine and Dentistry.
  - WRM to MM from Shih Men Kan, Beh Liu Tin, Chengtu, 1934 July-December (Box 4, Folder 74)
    Including regarding WRM's travels across the Szechuan province, characteristics and customs of the Miao people of China, WRM's thoughts on turning 60 years old, pressures at work, the growing reality of the Communist troubles in China, and MM's new experiences with working.
  - ACM to MM from Chengtu, 1934 January-June (Box 4, Folder 75)
    Describes political tensions in China, WRM's success with his lecture presentations, MM's commencement from Wellesley College, and the daily life events of ACM and MM.
  - ACM to MM from Beh Liu Tin, Chengtu, Hong Kong, 1934 July-December (Box 4, Folder 76)
    Including regarding WRM's trip across Szechuan province, rainstorms in Chengtu, warm weather, and events that ACM attends.
  - WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu, 1935 January-March (Box 4, Folder 77)
    Including description of unrest in China and resistance towards the Communist party, mail deliveries from foreign countries being held up and eventually coming through to China, WRM's optimism towards new medical students joining his classes in the face of Chinese Communism, and WRM's views on missionary work.
  - WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu, 1935 June-August (Box 4, Folder 78)
    Describes WRM and ACM's work with students and art exhibitions, visits with guests, housework developments and changes, worries and conflicts arise with the "Reds", WRM dropping out of office during the university's elections
  - WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu, Yachow, Shin Kai Si, 1935 June-August (Box 4, Folder 79)
    Including regarding MM's wedding engagement, WRM and ACM celebrating their 32nd wedding anniversary, the Nanking government requesting information from WRM and ACM, a lecture by Professor Weigle of the Yale Divinity School in Yachow, and WRM working on a paper called "The Ancient Aboriginal Tribes of Szechuan."
  - WRM and ACM to MM from boat on the Min River, Chengtu, 1935 September-October (Box 4, Folder 80)
    Describes WRM's happiness at MM's engagement and enthusiasm for work, the initiation of new members into the Christian Church Council, WRM's teaching processes of Anatomy and Surgery, and the death of the Morse family's friend Mrs. Williams.
  - WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu, 1935 November-December (Box 4, Folder 81)
    Describes the meetings of the United Church of Canada, the spread of communism to the living areas of Chinese tribes, Chinese students against Japan, earthquakes that have occurred in Szechuan province, and a sketch of where communism has spread in the Szechuan province.
  - ACM to MM from Chengtu, undated (Box 4, Folder 82)
    Including regarding ACM's city visits and visits with friends, painting, WRM and ACM giving students examinations, typhoon damages to Chinese houses.
  - WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu, 1936 January-March (Box 4, Folder 83)
    Describes MM's attendance at the Yale-Harvard football game, the annual West China Border Research Society conference at Chengtu, changes in Chinese culture and marriage customs, and WRM and ACM's visits with colleagues and friends.
  - WRM to MM from Chengtu, 1936 March-July (Box 4, Folder 84)
    Incluidng regarding the deaths of two friends of the Morse family, WRM's invitation to a conference for all of the Deans and Principals of the Medical College in China, MM receiving a letter from the president of the "Yale-in-China" Medical School (Edward H. Hume), Communists who are continually active, and political unrest in China.
  - WRM and ACM to MM from Kiating, Nanking, Chengtu, Beh Liu Tin, Miao country, 1936 April-July (Box 4, Folder 85)
    Describes WRM's time in Nanking as part of a trip conducted by the West China Union University and its medical college, MM contracting scarlet fever, WRM elected as director of the medical college of the West China Union University, and summer weather in Chengtu, Miao country, and Beh Liu Tin.
  - WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu, 1936 December (Box 5, Folder 86)
    WRM giving up hospital work and his position as director of the medical college in order to focus on anatomy and anthropology, Chinese feasts and customs for the start of the spring season, and a recipe for a Chinese meal.
  - WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu, Peu Hsien, 1936 August-November (Box 5, Folder 87)
    Describes government requirements for colleges and college classes, the customs and events of the Chinese Republic anniversary holiday "Double Truth Day", the Chinese goverment's set of counter-demands to Japan, and autumn weather in China.
  - WRM and ACM to MM from boat en route to Singapore, Colombo, London, 1937 April-August (Box 5, Folder 88)
    Incluidng description of the physical conditions of WRM and ACM, monotonous travel to Singapore by steamer boat, WRM trying to rewrite a paper on the blood groups of the Chinese Miao tribe, MM's wedding plans, participation in activities on a steamer boat to London, and WRM and ACM's positive experiences in London.
  - WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu, Chungking, Ichang, boat on the Yangtze River, Shanghai, 1937 January-April (Box 5, Folder 89)
    Describes the health recovery of WRM, WRM and ACM giving away many of their household items, WRM staying at home in order to rest and regain his health, MM's wedding date is planned and set, and travels to Chungking, Ichang, and Shanghai.
  - Fragments (Box 5, Folder 90)
- General Correspondence, 1912-1940; Series II
  - Correspondence to/from W.R. Morse (WRM)
    - W.R. Morse (WRM) to the First National Bank of Boston; WRM to Mr. Morrison; Stephen Yang to WRM; R. Gates to WRM from The University of London King's College, 1933-1939 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - Correspondence to WRM and Anne Crosse Morse (ACM)
    - Irene Chambers to WRM and ACM from Boston; May to WRM and ACM from Suifu, 1931-1939 (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Correspondence to ACM
    - From James M. Andrews, Ernest A. Hoolan, Board of Governors of the West China Union University, J.W. Decker, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - From Anne M. Salquist, A.B. Cunden, Ernest Hubbard, Ed Cunningham, Y.T. Beh, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - From S.H. Fong, Mrs. Cunningham, Anne M. Salquist, Leslie G. Kilborn, Joseph Chandler Robbins, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - From E.C. Wilford, West China Union University, May to ACM from Suifu., R. Eates from the University of London King's College, Anna M. Salquist, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - From T. Torrance, Fred Abrey, Tsu Ku Sze, Cheng Liang, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - Correspondence of others, 1921-1939
    - Harold to Elsie; Randolph S. Howard to relatives of the Morse family; Fred Haggard to mother of WRM, 1912, 1921, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 98)
- Writings and Notes, 1915-1936; Series III
  - Medical report by W.R. Morse (WRM) from Suifu and Chengtu, 1915 January 1 (Box 5, Folder 99)
  - Pages 2-7 of handwritten essay by W.R. Morse regarding Chinese medicine and his medical work, 1930-1931 (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - Articles by WRM, 1932-1936 (Box 5, Folder 101)
    Articles Included: "Opportunities for Graduate Work in West China" (Published in the Chinese Recorder," October, 1932); "An Expedition into the Chwan Miao Country: A Vacation with a Purpose" (Published in the W.C.U. Newsletter, October, 1936)
  - Book review of "The Three Crosses in the Purple Mist" by WRM, undated (Box 5, Folder 102)
    Published in the West China Missionary News, written by "J.T."
  - Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 103)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1929-1941; Series IV
  - Biographical documentation regarding W.R. Morse (WRM), 1928-1939 (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - Farewell Speech to Dr. and Mrs. Morse from Anatomy Class, 1929 November 29 (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - Notice in minutes of West China Union University College of Medicine and Dentistry regarding William Reginald and Anne Crosse Morse Memorial Fund, 1941 September 18 (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - Notice regarding publications of Royal Anthropological Institute, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 107)
  - Friendship calendar with notes and photographs from supporters, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 108)
  - Photograph, cards, wedding invitation, Chinese language material, 1911, undated (Box 5, Folder 109)